Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. JWT Corporate Archives records, 1971-1987 and undated RL.11404
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. JWT Corporate Archives records
1971-1987 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11404
3.5 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. Collection includes correspondence, accession records, collection inventories and finding aids, reports on JWT company and office histories, and transcripts of interviews with JWT executives. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. JWT Corporate Archives records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1987.
Collection Overview
Includes correspondence, accession records, collection inventories and finding aids, reports on JWT company and office histories, and transcripts of interviews with JWT executives. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising agencies -- United States -- Management; Advertising agencies -- United States -- History; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
- JWT Archives Records, 1971-1987 and undated; 1
  - Accession logs, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Accession records, 1979-1986; 8 folders (Box 1)
  - Accession records, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Accessions project, undated, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Advertisement collections (binder), undated, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Archives chronological correspondence and memos, 1982-1984; 7 folders (Box 2)
  - Archives progress reports, 1979-1987 (Box 2)
  - Finding aids (binder), undated, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Finding aids (binder), undated, 5 folders (Box 3)
  - General collection inventories (binder), undated, 5 folders (Box 3)
  - General collection inventories (binder), undated, 5 folders (Box 4)
  - Inquiries, 1983-1987; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - JWT Detroit Office history presentation, 1985 (Box 4)
  - JWT History and heritage presentation, undated, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - JWT West history presentation, undated (Box 4)
  - Nancy Fitzpatrick files: Archives, JWT history, 1977-1980 (Box 4)
  - Oral history interviews transcripts, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Oral history interviews transcripts, 1987; 8 folders (Box 5)
  - Procedures and policy manual for Archives, 1984 and undated; 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Radio and TV accessions, undated (Box 5)
  - Shelf lists, 1983-1986; 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Stanley Resor file, undated (Box 5)
  - Transfer of archives to Duke, 1987 (Box 5)
  - Card files and backup computer disks (obsolete format), undated (Box 6)
    Scope and Contents
    Card Files: Index to JWT Seminars; RG7 Artifacts and Memorabilia location guides; Radio/TV microfilm